{"pageProps":{"quizData":[{"id":"20","question":"Which of the following activities do we perform while declaring useState in react?","options":["Object destructuring","Unpacking object","Array destructuring","Unpacking array"],"correctAnswer":"3","explanation":"UseState() return an array containing two elements first state and second a function to alter that state, and through Array destructing we directly associate them with two variable."},{"id":"21","question":"Which type of variable can we define in the useState hook?","options":["Integer","String","List","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"4","explanation":"UseState allows us to define all kinds of datatype."},{"id":"22","question":"Can we use useState hook inside conditional statement such as: if or while?","options":["Yes","No"],"correctAnswer":"2","explanation":"Because react keeps the count of useState calls and expects the same number of calls each time."},{"id":"23","question":"How react remembers which state variable belongs to which useState call?","options":["It makes a lookup table","It remembers the calling order","It traverses the calls again, whenever needed","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"2","explanation":"This is how react knows which state belongs to which call."},{"id":"24","question":"How many calls we can make for useState or useEffect in a single component?","options":["Unlimited, but equal calls for both hooks","Unlimited","Limited","Limited, but equal calls for both hooks"],"correctAnswer":"2","explanation":"React does not restrict the number of calls."},{"id":"25","question":"Can we use useState and useEffect hooks simultaneously in a component?","options":["Yes","No","Depends on the condition"],"correctAnswer":"1","explanation":"React allows us, to use both hooks simultaneously in a component."},{"id":"26","question":"What does useState() return in React?","options":["Object","Json","Array","Integer"],"correctAnswer":"3","explanation":"UseState() return an array, containing state and a function which is then destructed using Array destructing and associate with two variable."},{"id":"27","question":"What is passed as an argument in useState() in React?","options":["Initial value","State variable","Function to set state","All can be passed"],"correctAnswer":"1","explanation":"Argument in useState() is the initial value we want to assign to the state."},{"id":"28","question":"Which datatype can be passed as an argument in useState() in React?","options":["String","Json","Integer","All of these"],"correctAnswer":"4","explanation":"UseState() can take any datatype defined in React."},{"id":"29","question":"How many possible arguments useState() can take?","options":["More than 2","Only 1","Exactly 2","No limit"],"correctAnswer":"2","explanation":"UseState() can take only one argument which is the initial value of the state."}],"title":"useState React Hook Quiz","description":"Quiz on react most used useState hook."},"__N_SSG":true}